<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Fernando's Website]]></title><description><![CDATA[My personal portfolio and blog]]></description><link>http://fernandoremde.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 21:14:24 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Standing Desks]]></title><link>http://fernandoremde.com/blog/standing-desk/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://fernandoremde.com/blog/standing-desk/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 18:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I have recently &quot;acquired&quot; a standing desk after reading so much about it. I use the term acquire loosely here because I just grabbed an old bar desk we have here at my home and put my monitor on top of a box and, lo and behold, a standing desk. The main reason for that were the benefits to posture, hips and back. I have been suffering with serious posture problems for my whole life and, even though everything is much better now after consistently lifting weights and stretching, I still could use some improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The first days&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, they sucked hard. For the first 3 or so days I couldn&apos;t even stand properly on my feet at the end of the day. I was still sitting a little (on the couch for the lack of a better option in my current &quot;office&quot;), but only 20% of the time. But I decided to stick with it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started to get better a week later. I sat down to watch some Udemy videos and realized I wasn&apos;t paying as much attention as I was earlier. Then I realized that it was because, while standing, my concentration levels were much higher. I wouldn&apos;t feel sleepy, I wouldn&apos;t randomly lose focus. And then all of the sudden I realized that, yeah, I should just stay up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion so far&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&apos;m tackling a hard problem, doing some mindless grind, or writing a blog post, I&apos;d rather sit. Or lay down. Or something in between. But still force myself to be up for at least 30-50% of the time. When I&apos;m learning, or doing something that requires my attention but doesn&apos;t require me to problem solve, I go like 90% up 10% sit. It&apos;s done wonders for my back as well. Much less soreness, my hips are much less tight, my hamstrings and core feel stronger and my feet don&apos;t hurt anymore. I&apos;d definitely recommend trying to stay up.</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Blogging is Back]]></title><link>http://fernandoremde.com/blog/hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://fernandoremde.com/blog/hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s crazy that I own this domain since I was 16 — six years ago. At the time it started as a blog, too, but a
Wordpress blog with short stories and poems. I wouldn&apos;t show it to anyone, but nevertheless it ended up being the basis for a few lyrics of songs that I wrote in the past years. (Hope I can talk about music here, too).
&lt;h3&gt;Goals moving forward&lt;/h3&gt;
The main focus of this new iteration, however, is to have a more &quot;serious&quot; note to it, to document projects, talk about programming, technology, fitness, finance, etc. I love all kinds of art and I would never leave it out of any project of mine, but when I eventually write about it here it will have a bit more of an analytical, introspective tone to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there won&apos;t be short stories and poems! It&apos;s still a thing for me — I guess so at least, haven&apos;t written any in a while — but it still is more of a private, me-alone thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About the technology&lt;/h3&gt;
I have written this everywhere in the last days, but I finally settled for Gatsby which uses the React framework for front-end and generates these awesome static pages. I am also paying for a 5$ a month DigitalOcean droplet, which I strongly recommend, as my server to deploy to. They have amazing guides for everything as well, which is great. I was already familiar with hosting and remote servers (any Minecraft ex-addicts?), but even then the guides came in very handy. Excellent service.
&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>