<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Fernando's Website]]></title><description><![CDATA[My personal portfolio and blog]]></description><link>http://fernandoremde.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 21:55:50 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Blogging is Back]]></title><link>http://fernandoremde.com/blog/hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://fernandoremde.com/blog/hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s crazy that I own this domain since I was 16 — six years ago. At the time it started as a blog, too, but a
Wordpress blog with short stories and poems. I wouldn&apos;t show it to anyone, but nevertheless it ended up being the basis for a few lyrics of songs that I wrote in the past years. (Hope I can talk about music here, too).
&lt;h3&gt;Goals moving forward&lt;/h3&gt;
The main focus of this new iteration, however, is to have a more &quot;serious&quot; note to it, to document projects, talk about programming, technology, finance, etc. I love all kinds of art and I would never leave it out of any project of mine, but when I eventually write about it here it will have a bit more of an analytical, introspective tone to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there won&apos;t be short stories and poems! It&apos;s still a thing for me — I guess so at least, haven&apos;t written any in a while — but it still is more of a private, me-alone thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;About the technology&lt;/h3&gt;
I have written this everywhere in the last days, but I finally settled for Gatsby which uses the React framework for front-end and generates these awesome static pages. I am also paying for a 5$ a month DigitalOcean droplet, which I strongly recommend, as my server to deploy to. They have amazing guides for everything as well, which is great. I was already familiar with hosting and remote servers (any Minecraft ex-addicts?), but even then the guides came in very handy. Excellent service.
&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>